ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
磁芯章鱼X
翻译
桃小兔吃冰棒
showeryhe
翻译
煮粥达人
累  小酸奶!
翻译
静妹粒
冬麟
时间轴
chance-coco  念念
电脑狂人
第三季
第六集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
字幕组
ZiMuZu.tv
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
最新最快海外影视字幕下载
请登陆www.ZiMuZu.tv
马卡罗内制衣
思科系统
你是否想跟汤兰顿私聊  是
汤兰顿:
还顺利吧
卡梅豪伊:
跟我想的一样  但也算搞定了
汤兰顿:
肯定挺刺激吧
你是否想跟汤兰顿私聊  是
汤兰顿:
还顺利吧
卡梅豪伊:
跟我想的一样  但也算搞定了
汤兰顿:
肯定挺刺激吧
是啊  如果你喜欢看人尴尬又生气
卡梅豪伊:
汤兰顿:
还顺利吧
卡梅豪伊:
跟我想的一样  但也算搞定了
汤兰顿:
肯定挺刺激吧
卡梅豪伊:
是啊  如果你喜欢看人尴尬又生气
汤兰顿:
我有事要跟你说
还顺利吧
卡梅豪伊:
跟我想的一样  但也算搞定了
汤兰顿:
肯定挺刺激吧
卡梅豪伊:
是啊  如果你喜欢看人尴尬又生气
汤兰顿:
我有事要跟你说
卡梅豪伊:
说吧
汤兰顿:
我告诉我妈了  她很为我们高兴
卡梅豪伊:
她不会打电话过来吧
抱歉  也没什么  就是这边事儿挺多的
卡梅豪伊:
汤兰顿:
你要迟到了
谢谢你  马里奥
你的征途已结束  我们有新的任务给你
按B选关
汤兰顿:
你没事吧
卡梅豪伊:
现在跟唐娜的关系很糟
汤兰顿:
会好起来的
卡梅豪伊:
你怎么知道  可能会永远这么糟
汤兰顿:
会好起来的
卡梅豪伊:
你怎么知道  可能会永远这么糟
汤兰顿:
我就要过去了
你跟别人说了吗
卡梅  你还在吗
汤兰顿:
那台3090主机什么时候能送到
So when does that 3090 get delivered?
他们说今天下午五点前
They said by 5:00 P.M. today.
斯坦福的人周一来  是吗
And we've got Stanford on Monday, right?
思科和世通再下一周
Cisco and MCI the week after.
好好看看吧
I'd take a good look.
很快这里就会堆满了硬件  签许多协议
Soon it'll be hardware and handshake deals,
没完没了的除错和升级
endless troubleshooting and upgrades.
但现在  是完美的
But right now-- right now it's perfect.
房间吗
The room?
这个理念
The idea.
一切顺利的话  这个月底
All goes well, by the end of the month
我们就要向国家科学基金网的地区主管
we'll be sitting down with the sector chief of NSFNET
提出合作计划
to walk him through the bid.
他叫米奇·克劳顿
It's Mitch Klowden.
是我在IBM的老同事了
We go back to my IBM days.
是个好人  衣着很有品位
He's a good guy. Sharp dresser.
听上去很不错
Well, this all sounds fantastic.
我得和我的人商量一下
I have to discuss it with the team,
不过周一之前我回给你回话
but I should have an answer for you by Monday.
-很好  -还有你
- Excellent. - And you.
你从哪里挖来的
Where'd you find this one, hmm?
认识你很高兴  莱恩  头脑很灵光
Great to meet you, Ryan. Hell of a head on those shoulders.
谢谢  米奇
Thank you, Mitch.
衣服剪裁也很合身
And a nice cut on that suit.
米奇  很高兴再见到你
Mitch, it was great to see you again.
-彼此彼此  乔  -多谢赏光过来
- Great to see you, Joe. - Thank you for coming by.
我记错点了吗
Did I get the wrong time?
没  我也以为是这个点
No, your info's as good as mine.
小胖和瘦杆整天都没影
Haven't seen Mutt or Jeff all day.
两位女士都躲在各自的小窝里
And the ladies are in their respective foxholes
这似乎成了她们的习惯了
as seems to be their wont these days.
你有没有过想在这行里干一番大事
Do you ever try to be the bigger man in this business,
结果回报给你的只有几个烂果子的经历
but the universe just gives you a shit sandwich for your efforts?
那是当然有
Indeed I have.
但我要去看《图拉多》犒劳自己
But I'm treating myself to "Turan-dot,"
所以也没啥可抱怨的
so I can't complain.
-什么  -《图拉多》
- What? - "Turan-dot."
那部歌剧
The opera.
我要开拓自己的眼界
I'm broadening my horizons.
熟悉这地方
Know my new town.
那叫《图兰朵》吧
It's "Turandot."
抱歉几位  我接个电话晚了
Sorry, guys. I got stuck on a call.
好了  我们开始吧
Okay, let's get started.
要不要等等道格和克雷格
Uh, shouldn't we wait for Doug and Craig?
那就要白等了
That would be a waste of time.
-为什么  -我把他们开了
- Why? - I fired them.
什么时候
When?
就今早
This morning.
为什么啊
Why?
跳蚤市场已经完全整合好了
Well, SwapMeet's fully integrated
现金支付组件也没有错误了
and the cash feature's bug-free,
所以不需要他们了
so I no longer need them.
那该给他们的预期盈利怎么办
And what are we going to do about their earn-out?
我觉得黛安的意思是希望我们好好合作
I feel like Diane was pretty clear she wanted us to make it work.
是吗
Was she?
当然  我
Yeah, I mean...
你怎么不
why would you--
我只是希望你先跟我们商量下
I just wish you'd discussed it with us first.
抱歉  黛安·古德来了  要见你们二位
Sorry, Diane Gould is here for both of you.
好啊  肯定是好事
Oh, should be fun.
我得承认我吃了一惊
Well, I must admit I'm surprised.
我以为你们已经协调好工作流程了
I thought you all had found a manageable workflow.
我们讨论了一下  然后决定
Well, we discussed it and we decided
道格和克雷格的作用已经充分发挥完了
that Doug and Craig's usefulness had run its course.
根据我们之前的讨论  我们都认为
And we both figured based on our earlier conversations
你会支持我们的决定
that you'd have our backs on this.
我之前说过  我会批准付款的
Well, as I've said, I'll authorize the earn-out
既然你们都决定了
if that's what you feel you need.
但我今天来不是说这个
But that's not what I'm here to discuss.
我有个消息
I have news.
有人向你们提出了收购邀约
You have an acquisition offer.
对方是计算机服务
From CompuServe.
计算机服务
CompuServe?
我知道  我也觉得不太合适
I know. I don't think it's a good fit either,
但给了一个底价
but it sets a floor.
多少
How much?
两千万
20 million.
那是之前西方集团报价的四倍
That's four times what Westgroup offered.
我们的成长真有那么迅速吗
I mean, have we really grown that fast?
事情是这样的  我也没想到
Here's the thing, and I didn't think
会这么快就跟你们谈这个
we'd be having this conversation so soon,
但我认为现在可以
but I think it's a good time
考虑首次公开募股了
to consider the possibility of an IPO.
有大笔资金注入就可以做很多事
The things we could do with that influx of cash.
好吧  但这钱也不能随便花  对吧
Okay, it's not like we'd get to spend the money, though, right?
因为得建董事会  追求季度收益
I mean, we'd have to get a board and chase quarterly earnings.
那是当然  但也该想想其前景
Absolutely, but it's also important to consider the landscape.
看看甲骨文收购升阳
Look at Sun, Oracle.
想想微软筹到的钱
I mean, Jesus, the money that Microsoft has raised.
再说眼下穆特尼
Plus right now Mutiny is the
是在线交易市场的巨头
dominant player in the online transaction market.
他们一听到这个报价
Once they hear the news of this offer,
都会跟风
there'll be imitators.
想想呀
I mean, just think,
我们一直想做的那些事
everything we've ever wanted to play with.
我们还可以组一个研发团队
We could hire a whole team for R&D.
行了  我才不会把公司剁成碎渣
Yeah, okay, I'm not chopping my company up into pieces
让你们去华尔街摇铃上市
so that you can ring a bell on Wall Street.
好了  这是件大事
Okay, this is just a lot.
我得花时间消化
I need time to process it.
当然  你去想吧
Sure, okay. You think about it.
慢慢想  爱想多久想多久
Take all the time you need.
这个决定很重大
This is a huge decision
你们俩都该好好考虑一番
and both of you should take a lot of time with it.
但不管你们怎么回事  都该处理一下
But whatever you have going on here, you need to deal with it.
这样吧  我在索诺马有套房子
I'll tell you what. I have a place up in Sonoma.
一个小葡萄园  环境安宁
It's a little vineyard. It's quite peaceful.
很适合整理思绪
It's a good place to get your thoughts in order.
要不你们周末去那儿吧
Why don't you guys go there, take the weekend,
达成一致
get on the same page?
乐意之至
We'd love to.
很好
Great.
周末我都有空
I'll be around all weekend
欢迎来找我谈
if you want to talk any of this through.
谢谢  黛安  非常感谢
Thanks, Diane. Really.
你想今晚还是明天开车去
So do you want to drive up tonight or tomorrow?
嗯  那个
Yeah, uh, well,
虽然跟你一起去葡萄园听上去十分浪漫
while a wine farm retreat with you sounds super romantic,
可我这周末很忙
I am busy this weekend.
现代社会建立在
Modern society sits on a foundation
如今被我们视为理所当然的服务上
of services we now take for granted.
铁路
Railroads.
高速公路
Highways.
水
Water.
能源
Power.
网络运算将会成为下一个重要的公共服务
Network computing will be the next great public utility.
我的工作已经让我们位居前沿
My actions have placed us at the vanguard
我们可以收获巨额回报
and we are poised to reap vast rewards.
美国早期的企业家们受时空所束缚
America's early entrepreneurs were bound by space and time.
而这个新网络将是无限的
This new network will be limitless.
那个  我问问清楚
Just-- I just-- just to be clear,
国家...
the N--
国家科学基金网是非营利的  对吧
The NSFNET is nonprofit, right?
只用于科研实验室  政府和大学
It's just for research labs and governments and colleges.
-没有商用  -对
- There is no commercial use? - That's correct.
-在第...  -22页
- On page-- - 22.
有泰勒-恩斯特战略公司的备忘录
There's a memo from Taylor and Ernst Strategies.
他们预计会有五年的立法过程
They anticipate a five-year legislative process.
我们已经在3090主机上花了六百万
And we've already spent six million on the 3090
在路由器和交换机上花了四十万
and another 400,000 on routers and switches.
等等  既然有这些速度和容量问题
Wait, with these speed and capacity issues,
为什么我们要投资买
why are we investing in faster equipment
比网络承受速度快的设备
than the network can bear?
现在只有56K  但是所有迹象
It's only 56K now, but all signs
都表明很快会升级到T1网线
point to a T1 upgrade coming soon.
各位  我理解你们的疑虑
Guys, I understand the skepticism.
无可否认这是一次大胆的期货赌博
There's no denying this is a bold futures bet,
但这是必然趋势
but it is a sure one.
可能会需要点时间  但是终会赚钱的
It may take some time, but the money will come.
先生们  不如我们这样
You know what, gentlemen? Why don't we do this?
不如我们趁这个周末
Why don't we take the weekend
消化一下这个惊人的提议
to digest this impressive proposal?
你们说呢  好吗
What do you say? Yeah?
很好  非常感谢
Good. Thank you very much.
谢谢
Thank you.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thank you. - Pleasure.
-再见到你真好  -谢谢
- Great to see you again. - Thank you.
你欠我一局球
Hey, you owe me 18.
见到你真好  替我向贝基问好
Hey, good seeing you. Say hi to Becky for me, okay?
我喜欢这雄心  真的
I love the ambition. I do.
-我只需要你慢一点  -等待就会失败
- I just need you to slow down. - We wait, we lose.
我明白  真的  我也相信你的远见
I hear you, I do. And I believe in your vision.
所以我才在这儿  但是拜托  乔...
That's why I'm here, but please, Joe...
别再买东西了
no more purchases.
别再做承诺
No promises.
让他们同意
Just get them on board.
那才是你的作用
That's why you're here.
过程就是这样  知道吧
Well, this is the process, you know?
你该看看我告诉他们
You should have seen their faces
城堡要免费时  他们的表情
when I told them the Citadel was going to be free.
今天干得不错
Good work today.
什么事
Yeah?
你确定不介意我去吗
Are you sure you don't mind me going?
不介意  没事  没事的
No, it's fine. It's fine.
我很感激
Well, I appreciate it.
我真的需要离开卡梅伦一段时间
I really need some time away from Cameron.
我就需要那么一个小时的安宁  行吗
And I just need one damn hour of peace, okay?
-孩子们认为这地方  -天哪
- The girls think this place is-- - Oh, my God.
-唐娜  -宝贝  对不起
- Donna! - Babe, I'm so sorry.
-你要哪个  -这个
- Which one do you want? - This one.
谢谢
Thank you.
你在跟谁说话
Who you talking to?
就是一些人
Just some guys.
我很高兴你玩得开心
Well, I'm glad you're having fun.
不  抱歉
No! Ah! Sorry.
等等  慢点  你会错过金币房
Now, wait, wait. Slow down, you're gonna miss the coin room.
-在哪里  -左边的管子进去
- Where? - The tube on the left.
-不过要小心水虎鱼  -不不
- But watch out for the piranha. - No! No!
-现在能让我们玩了吗  -等一下
- Can we please play now? - In a second.
我们更擅长打大怪物
We're better at the bosses.
那你怎么死了
Then how come you're dead?
孩子们  你们都出去行吗
Look, guys, why don't y'all go outside, okay?
外面天气很好
It's nice out.
等我们打完水下世界的
Just till we finish this world.
那可是140个小时后
But that'll be 40 and 100 hours.
你们去外面  骑会儿单车
Look, you guys go outside, ride some bikes.
你们一回来  就到你们玩  我保证
As soon as you get back, okay, you can have a turn. I promise.
-随便吧  -这是琼妮的任天堂
- Whatever. - It's Joanie's Nintendo anyway.
我们今天玩通关
Let's beat the game today.
来吧  唐娜不在
Come on, Donna's away.
不然还能什么时候玩
When else are we gonna do it?
我们先看看孩子们回来前能过多少关
Let's just see how far we get before the girls get back.
如果我们能跳过水下世界就好了
If we could just skip the water world.
我讨厌水下世界
I hate the water world.
"你的公主在另一座城堡里"
"Your princess is in another castle."
如果我们这次过不了
Look, if we don't beat it this time,
那我今天就得到此为止了
then I think I gotta call it quits for the day.
行吗
Okay?
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
-好  -太棒了
- Yes. - Yes!
-我去  -终于可以选关了
- Holy shit! - Welcome to the warp zone!
天啊  真不敢相信花了这么长时间
Oh, God, I can't believe it took me this long.
给你  你来  你擅长云彩那关
Here, here, here. You go. You're better at the cloud level.
好
Okay.
-开始了  看我的  -好  好
- Oh, it's on now. It's on now. - Yes, yes.
-过来  你个长刺的大屁股龟  -我的天
- Come here, you spiny, turtle-birthing butt. - Oh, my God.
弄死它  当心
Yes, kill it. Watch out.
戈登
Gordon?
戈登  天啊
Gordon? Jesus Christ.
-戈登  你还好吗  -还好
- Gordon, are you okay? - Yeah.
-戈登  -我没事
- Gordon? - Yeah, I'm fine.
-你刚才是怎么了  -我很好
- What? What the hell just happened? - I'm fine.
我就是...
I just--
我需要吃点东西
I just need to eat something.
什么
What?
我很好
I'm fine.
-推  -我在推
- Push. - I am pushing.
可以了
Okay.
我不信
I'm not buying it.
你说你血糖低
The blood sugar excuse.
是神经的问题
It's neurological.
已经得了一年左右了
I've been dealing with it for about a year.
他们发现一个很小的区域萎缩了
They-- they found very small areas of atrophy.
严格说是退化性的  但...
So technically it's degenerative, but--
天啊
Jesus Christ.
-你要死了吗  -不
- So you're dying? - No.
不  我不会死
No, I'm not dying.
人人都会死
I mean, we're all-- we're all dying,
但不会的  已经得到控制了
but, no, it's under control.
我在吃药  大多数时候我都很好
I'm taking medication and most days I'm fine.
其他时候...
Other days--
你会一头栽到地上
You pile-drive a Zenith.
不  那个...
No, that's a--
只有这么一次
that was a first.
唐娜知道吗
Donna knows?
还有谁知道
Who else?
模糊球路由器的配置在什么地方
Where are the router configurations for the existing Fuzzballs?
应该是跟其他通用通讯交换装置的
Uh, they should be in the binder
研究在一个活页夹里
with the rest of the UCSD research.
好
Okay.
喂  我是乔
Yeah, this is Joe.
你好  米切尔  没想到你会周六打来
Hey, Mitch. Didn't expect to hear from you on a Saturday.
一切都还好吧
Is everything all right?
那是个好消息  天大的好消息
That's great news. Great news.
相信我  我的心情也和你一样
I assure you the feeling is mutual.
米切尔  我们该聘你来做公关
Mitch, we should hire you to run PR.
我也是
Yeah, me, too.
听我说
Uh, hey, listen.
协议文件周一送过来
Messenger over the paperwork on Monday
我会让我的律师尽快过一遍的
and I'll have my lawyers go through it ASAP.
好  回头再聊
Yeah, we'll be talking.
恭喜
Hey, congrats.
你上车了
You made it on the train.
那个通用通讯交换装置文件夹在哪
Where's that UCSD binder?
我们该庆祝一下
We should celebrate.
庆祝
Celebrate?
他们刚批准的提议大半还是理论
That bid they just approved is half fiction.
现在我们要把它变成现实
Now we make it real.
来  我们开始吧
Come on, let's get to it.
但是  乔
But, Joe,
现在它是完美的
right now it's perfect.
你喝过30年的苏格兰威士忌吗
Have you ever had 30-year-old scotch?
-你是谁  -天啊
- Hello? - Oh, my God!
你是黛安的女儿吧
Oh, you're Diane's daughter.
我从照片中认出你了
I recognize you from the pictures.
我是唐娜·克拉克  你妈妈的同事
I'm Donna Clark. I work with your mom.
不好意思
Sorry.
我是金柏莉
Yes, I'm Kimberly.
-金米  没事吧  -我没事  没事
- Kimmie, everything okay? - Oh, I'm fine. It's fine.
这是唐娜  我妈的同事
This is Donna. She works with my mom.
这是我男朋友  崔维斯
This is my boyfriend Travis.
还有他的室友罗博
And his roommate Rob.
你好
Hello.
这是我妈的毛衣吗
Is that my mom's sweater?
我刚刚在洗澡
I was just in the bath.
很抱歉  我可以去找个旅馆的
I'm so sorry. I can go get a hotel.
不用  不用  不用
No, no, no, no. Please.
我们今天刚决定从伯克利开车过来
We just decided to drive up from Berkeley today.
我们完全可以开回去的
We can totally drive back.
别  不要这样
Oh, no, don't do that.
没关系  我来之前
No, it's fine. I'm kind of supposed to ask
该问一下的
before I come up here anyway.
瞧  这个房子很大
Well, look, it's a huge house.
我带来的食物太多了吃不完
I brought more food than I can possibly eat.
不如这样  我不跟你妈说我见到你了
So what about this-- I don't tell your mom I saw you
你也别说我穿她的衣服怎么样
and we keep it between us that I was trying on her clothes?
太扯了
That's insane.
可不是
Yeah, I know.
你考虑了吗
Did you consider it?
有点吧  那毕竟是一笔巨财的70%
Sort of. I mean, it was 70% of a fortune.
想收买人心可不便宜
Well, souls don't come cheap.
你在水下关卡怎么这么厉害
I don't understand how you're so good at the underwater level.
天赋
It's a gift.
我其实并不在乎钱
You know, I don't even really care about the money.
我只想让他承认自己的所作所为
I just want him to admit what he did.
嗯
Yeah.
你可以的
All right, you can do this.
-好  -我相信你
- Okay. - I believe in you.
要是能朝乔扔火球...
Wish I could pelt Joe with fireball...
别
Don't.
终于啊
Yeah! Finally!
-过关了  -终于啊
- Victory! - Finally.
-想看个有趣的东西吗  -好啊
- You want to see something cool? - Yeah.
射频频谱像一把长尺
The radio spectrum's like a long measuring tape.
调幅控制低频
The AM band's the low frequency.
在底部
And it's down here on the bottom.
调频在顶端
And the FM is way up here on the top.
明白吗
You follow?
戈登  说实话
Man, Gordon, I got to be honest.
之前我不知道你在鼓捣什么
I didn't know what you were doing in here,
但这真是太酷了
but this is pretty rad.
你真这么想  其实挺傻的
You really think so? I mean, it's kind of silly.
不  我真心觉得很酷
No, no, I mean it. I think it's cool.
要是唐娜也这么想就好了
Yeah, well, I wish Donna shared your enthusiasm.
你要知道  你做了件很难得的事
You know, I hope you realize what a rare thing you've done.
你和唐娜
You and Donna.
你俩真的做出了一番事业
I mean, you guys built something real.
你也一样
Yeah, so did you.
拜托  不用这么客气
Oh, please. You don't have to do that.
我制造的机器无人会铭记
I built a couple of machines no one will remember
做的软件大家都以为是乔做的
and a piece of software everybody thinks is Joe's.
不说那个混蛋了
Enough about that jackass.
试试吧
Let's fire this thing up.
奇怪  昨晚还好好的
That's weird. I was just talking on it last night.
可能接触不良
Maybe there's a loose connection.
你确定吗
Oh, you sure about that?
来
Here.
启动吧
Fire it up.
CQ
CQ.
你好
Hey there.
能给我倒
Could I just get two fingers
两指威士忌吗
of something brown back there?
你听到了吗
Did-- did you hear?
我们能假装
Could we just pretend
你为我占了一个位置吗
that you were holding a place in line for me?
瞧瞧谁来了
Well, look who it is.
这位小姐要一杯金汤力
Uh, this young lady will have a gin and tonic
加一片酸橙  谢谢
with lime, please.
-你有伴吗  -没有  一个人
- Are you here with someone? - No, flying solo.
没办法  我和普契尼是老交情了
What can I say? Me and Puccini go way back.
你呢
You?
相亲
It's a blind date.
他是某个银行家的朋友的朋友
He's a friend of a friend of a banker or something.
我都忘了为什么会来这里
I forget how I ended up here.
很高兴认识你  多莉斯
I have enjoyed our time together, Doris.
谢谢
Gracias.
谢谢你救了我
Well, thank you for saving me.
你看上去可不像需要人救的女人啊
You don't strike me much like a woman needs saving.
听着
Hey, listen.
我来的时候经过了一家酒吧  看起来不错
There's a bar I pass on the way here. Looks like a good time.
演出结束后我们可以再去喝杯鸡尾酒
We can get another cocktail after the show.
给我两分钟  我们门外会和
Give me two minutes. I'll meet you outside.
敬我  多莉斯
Here's to me, Doris.
当然了  他完全不见踪影
But, of course, he is nowhere to be found.
紧急出口也紧锁  把我关在了外面
And, of course, the emergency exit locks behind me.
我一丝不挂  醉醺醺的
So I'm totally naked, super drunk
警报大作  他和我的外套
with this alarm blaring and he and my coat
在另一扇门里  但我完全不知道
are at a different door, but I didn't know that.
所以我一路跑回了寝室
So I ran all the way back to my dorm
像动画片里的间谍一样拿灌木丛遮身
ducking behind bushes like some cartoon spy.
幸好那是期末周  学校里没什么人
Thank God it was finals week and no one was around.
希望你跟他分手了
I hope you broke up with him.
事实上我嫁给了他
I married him, actually.
不会吧
Oh, no.
真不敢相信你真在阿·古·吉工作
I can't believe you actually work at AGG.
不  你妈妈是我公司的一名投资者
Oh, no, no, your mom's an investor in my company.
是一家叫穆特尼的在线服务公司
It's an online service called Mutiny.
少来  少来啦
Shut up. Shut up.
-你是穆特尼的老板  -半个老板
- You own Mutiny? - Yeah, a part of it.
等等  你是卡梅豪伊吗
Wait, are you CamHowe?
真是疯狂  我是预计先知
This is insane. I'm EstimatedProphet.
不  卡梅是我的合伙人
No, no, Cam is my partner.
它最棒了  我找一盘
It's like the best. I'd been looking for a tape
77年6月冰封大地演出的录像带好几年了
of this June '77 Winterland show for literally years.
注册穆特尼后  20分钟就找到了
Signed up on Mutiny, found it 20 minutes later.
太棒了
That's great.
唐娜  你和我妈该交朋友
So, Donna, you and my mom should be friends.
我们就是朋友
Oh, I think we are friends.
不  我是说  真朋友
No, yeah, I mean, friend friends.
我妈只有工作上的朋友
'Cause all my mom's got are work friends
其他都是爸爸的朋友
and everyone else was Dad's.
打造一家公司  还挂上自己的姓氏
Well, I'm sure it took a lot of nights and weekends
肯定是要下很大功夫的
to build a firm with her name on the door.
肯定很不容易
That couldn't have been easy.
但那也是爸爸的姓氏  这很糟糕
Except the name's Dad's, too, which sucks.
我觉得你风趣聪明
I just think you're fun and smart
她肯定很喜欢你
and she must really like you
因为她没让几个人来过这儿
'cause she does not let a lot of people up here.
我也喜欢她
Well, I like her, too.
你们还有大麻吗
Hey, you guys, do you have any of that pot left?
有  但是
Well, yeah, but...
怎么了
What?
或许你想试试别的
If you're maybe looking for a different sort of adventure.
我要坦白一件事
So I have a confession.
说吧
Shoot.
我不怎么喜欢德州
I don't care much for Texas.
为什么
Why ever not?
不就是一群德州汉子
Isn't it just a bunch of good old boys
开着横跨绝尘而去吗
in Dixie Trans Ams speeding down dirt roads?
那是佐治亚州  而且李将军是辆战马
That'd be Georgia. And the General Lee is a Charger.
-好吧  -你是没去过吧
- Okay. - Never been, I take it.
是啊
No, I have not.
跟我讲讲
Tell me about it.
跟其他地方一样
Well, it's like any other place
但更多一番风情
except more so.
是吗  就像这里吗
Really? Like this place?
我们什么样都有
Well, we get all kinds.
我得承认  走进来时可没想到会是这番景象
Have to admit, not what I had in mind when we walked in here,
但很高兴我们进来了
but glad we did.
你在那儿还有家人  是吗
So you still have family there, yeah?
来
Here.
看看这小家伙
That little feller.
天呐  他真可爱
Oh, my God. He's beautiful.
嗯
Yeah.
真是难以置信  是吧
It's a hell of a thing, ain't it?
天呐  感觉好像就几天前
God, it feels like it was just a few days ago
我还在给金编辫子
that I was braiding Kim's hair.
现在  她再有一年就从伯克利毕业了
And now she has one year left at Berkeley.
人们都说白驹过隙
Everybody says it passes so fast.
我说不清
I don't know.
我工作那么忙  错过了好多
Working as much as I do, I missed a lot.
是啊  我也是
Yeah, you and me both.
我以为自己要在德州退休的  能常看到他们
I thought I was gonna retire in Texas. You know, be around.
每个月带小萨姆去看几场球赛
I'd take little Sam to a ball game a couple times a month.
我想能告诉他  我做过有意义的事
I wanted to be able to tell him I did things that mattered.
而现在我的故事没人想听
Now I got stories no one cares about.
我这年纪说这话真傻
Foolish things coming from a man my age.
抱歉
Apologies.
不  不必道歉
No, not at all.
先生们  请欢迎
Gentlemen, welcome to the stage
非凡女士
Lady Divine.
戈登
Gordon?
我没吵醒你吧
I didn't wake you, did I?
没有  我正要出去
No, no, I'm just heading out.
好吧
Okay, uh...
晚安了
well, good night.
-卡梅  -怎么
- Hey, Cam. - Yeah?
今天真好玩
It was really fun today.
是啊
Yeah, it was.
再见  戈登
Bye, Gordon.
你来了
You came.
我们该谈谈
I figured we should talk.
来  坐下
Come, sit with me.
我不喜欢这样
I don't like this.
我不喜欢这种感觉
I don't like feeling this way.
我也是
I hate it, too.
我不知道怎么会变成这样
I don't know how we got here.
你骗了我  唐娜
You lied to me, Donna.
我知道  但我
I know, but I--
当时并没觉得像撒谎
it didn't feel like a lie at the time.
而是觉得那样对公司更好
It felt like what was best for the company,
对你更好
like what was best for you.
我跟你一样厉害的
I am just as good at this as you are.
从没有人说过你不是
No one ever said you weren't.
他们不用说出来
They don't have to say it.
时刻能感觉到
It's there all the time.
那声音震耳欲聋  卡梅是天才  唐娜是妈妈
It's deafening. Cam is the genius. Donna is the mom.
那我们又退回原地了
So we're back where we started.
不
No.
还没呢
No, not yet.
看看这里
I mean, look at this place.
你想过我们能来到这儿吗
Did you ever think we'd be here?
你要听多少遍
How many times do you need
没有你我是做不到的
to hear that I can't do this without you?
很抱歉我骗了你
I'm sorry that I lied to you.
我原谅你
I forgive you.
-好吧  -好吧
- Well... - Well...
-没想到今晚会发展成这样  -我也是
- Not the night I was expecting. - Nor I.
跟我回家喝一杯吧
Why don't you come back to the house for a nightcap?
有点晚了
You know, it's getting a little late.
我送你回车上吧
Let me just-- I'll just drop you back at your car.
我可以...
You know, I could-- I could...
过去的
come by.
不用了
No, it's fine.
你得承认戈登的原创
You need to give Gordon credit.
随你生我气
Be pissed at me.
你有这权利
You have every right.
但是别拿戈登撒气
Just, Jesus, don't take it out on Gordon.
他需要这个
He needs this.
乔  你得对得起他
Joe, do right by him.
承认他创造了什么
Give him credit for what he built.
说话啊
Say something.
我们庆祝吧
Shall we celebrate?
为什么
Why?
你戴的是结婚戒指吧
That's a wedding ring on your finger, isn't it?
我是来谈戈登的
I came here to talk about Gordon.
是吗
Did you?
现在是凌晨1:30
It's 1:30 in the morning.
你在走廊里等我
You were waiting in my hallway.
就为了谈戈登
To talk about Gordon?
是那个谁吗
Is it what's his name?
无所谓了  可能是任何人
It doesn't matter. Could have been anyone.
你觉得开心  就以为是因为
You were happy for a moment and you thought the person
那个站得离你最近的人
standing closest to you was the source.
相信我
Trust me.
我也有过这种经历
I've been there.
你得承认戈登的原创
You need to give Gordon credit.
有人吗
Hello.
有人吗  我回来了
Hello, I'm home.
妈妈
Mommy, Mommy!
这是怎么回事
What is all this?
卡梅伦打坏了电视  爸爸就买了台新的
Cameron broke the TV, so Daddy bought a new one.
多大啊
Isn't it so big?
是啊  真大  宝贝
Yeah, it sure is, baby.
那儿怎么样
How was it?
很好  可棒了
It was great. Really great.
我觉得神清气爽
I feel clearer.
你吃多少那个了
Hey, how many of those have you had?
就这一个
Only this one.
-她打坏了电视  -说来话长
- She broke the TV, huh? - Yeah, long story.
好吧  她在吗
Okay. Is she home?
她出去了
Well, she-- she went out--
她很晚出去的  我也没听到她回来
she went out late and I didn't hear her come in.
卡梅  卡梅伦
Cam. Cameron.
等等  唐娜  她可能在睡呢
Hold up, Donna. She could be asleep.
卡梅
Cam?
Cam.
天呐
Oh, my God.
戈登
Gordon?
-卡梅伦  -它好使
- Cameron? - It works!
你今天没去办公室
You weren't in the office today.
是啊  我需要一天把这玩意组装起来
Yeah, well, I needed a day to put this thing together.
你怎么没告诉我们你搬走了
Why didn't you tell us you moved out?
我结婚了
I got married.
不  我认真的
No, I'm serious.
我跟汤姆在德州结婚了
I got married to Tom back in Texas.
太棒了
That's incredible.
我真替你开心
I'm really happy for you.
谢谢
Thanks.
我也很开心
I'm happy, too.
我不知道你今天也要来参加
I didn't know you were gonna be in this thing today.
我不参加
I'm not.
我推迟了取证  我们得谈谈
I postponed the depo. We need to talk.
请坐
Have a seat.
不购买  不许诺
No purchases and no promises.
我们说好的
That's what we said.
今早  我收到一份传真
This morning I got a copy of a fax
是国家科学基金网的律师发来的
from the NSFNET lawyers came across my desk.
于是我打给米奇·克劳顿想问个清楚
So when I called Mitch Klowden for clarification,
他说  你俩周末时曾进行过愉快的对话
he said that the two of you had a lovely conversation this weekend
所以我们现在在合作了
and that we're now in business.
得了  肯  坐下
Come on, Ken, just sit down.
你完了
You're done.
我今早集合了董事会
I gathered the board this morning
我们投票解除了你的行政权
and we voted to remove your executive authority
并取消了国家科学基金网的交易
and kill the NSFNET deal.
肯
Ken.
当然  你完全可以辞职
Of course you're more than welcome to quit,
但我们打算执行四年的不可竞争条款
but we plan to enforce the four-year noncompete.
我劝你
So if I was you,
还是继续来上班吧  麦克米伦先生
I'd just keep showing up for work, Mr. MacMillan.
像坐山佛一样
Just sit up in that office of yours
坐在你的办公室里
like Buddha on the goddamn mountain
向科技媒体兜售鬼话
dispensing pearls of nonsense to the tech press,
但你再也别想
but you will never
花麦克米伦实用网络的钱
spend another MacMillan Utility dime,
启动其他项目或发号施令
launch another project or give another order.
你也别想拿消防软管
And before you even dream about running a fire hose
冲大办公室或搞其他什么花样
into the bullpen or some other such bullshit,
别忘了我们的律师起草的那些
I would meditate on the Joe MacMillan clause
针对你的条款
our lawyers had such fun drawing up.
你敢捣乱
One destructive move from you,
你所拥有的普通股就全部烟消云散了
and every point of equity you got goes up in smoke.
决定好了告诉我
Let me know what you decide.
请报上姓名
State your name.
乔·麦克米伦
Joe MacMillan.
所在公司和头衔
And your title and place of business, please.
麦克米伦实用网络  创始执行总裁
Founding CEO, MacMillan Utility.
作为执行总裁
And in your capacity as CEO,
你是否经常看到来自外界的软件点子
do you often review outside submissions for software ideas?
不  从没有过
No, never.
那么所有产品研发都是在公司内完成的
All product development is done in-house, then?
是的
Yeah, yeah.
请跟我讲讲这个流程
Walk me through that process, please.
麦克米伦先生
Mr. MacMillan?
是我偷的
I stole it.
-什么  -关掉
- What? - Turn that off.
-别  -关掉
-Don't. - Turn it off.
我  乔·麦克米伦
I, Joe MacMillan,
偷了戈登·克拉克的杀毒软件的代码
stole the code to the security software from Gordon Clark.
这家公司的根基是他的创造
Everything this this company's built on is his.